Alby Batista

Full-Stack Software Engineer - New York









☑ albybatista@gmail.com ② 917-750-5515 🍙 albybatista.com ② github.com/albybatista

LinkedIn

Summary

As a software developer, my favorite place is a blank text editor. Being a kinesthetic learner, all I've known from a young age has been how to build and break, in order to recreate. One of the most gratifying feelings is coming up with a solution to a problem and being able to immerse my solutions and creative mindset while collaborating with others. My foundation at General Assembly's bootcamp has allowed me to mesh both new and dormant passions in ways that I had never thought before possible as a developer.

Experience

Software Engineer Fellow @ General Assembly

July 2020 - November 2020 // Remote

- Attended General Assembly's award-winning 500-hour Software Engineering Immersive program covering front-end, back-end, and full-stack application development integrating object-oriented programming in both solo and team building collaborative environments
- Languages, frameworks, and topics covered included using and creating an API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), (¡Query, AJAX, Express, Node.js), React, MongoDB/Mongoose, Atlas, EJS, PHP, PostgreSQL, creating CRUD applications with RESTful routes, Single Page and Multi Page applications, and version control with Git and GitHub in scrum or agile development workflow

Retail Assistant Manager @ T-Mobile

August 2012 - November 2020 // Bronx, NY

- ▶ Winner's Circle 2015 Top 1% in sales nation-wide for the year, surpassing goals by a 200% margin and received T-Mobile's most prestigious sales and leadership award
- ▶ Carry out sales and administrative duties efficiently and professionally to meet and exceed business expectations
- ▶ Train and develop employees to build effective team building and sales tactics when executing their roles
- Use SalesForce, Workday, Slack and other software and interfaces to maximize business efficiency across upper, middle, and lower level management, employees, and clients
- Oversee multiple metrics and employees while operating a high-volume sales environment
- Execute inventory counts regularly and calculate revenue and deposits upon store closing calculating amounts over \$5,000 on a day-to-day basis

Field Energy Sales @ SolarCity

July 2014 - November 2014 // Westchester, NY

- Spearheaded and launched successful large-scale enrollment in cost efficient and eco-friendly energy
- ▶ Consult homeowners on financial benefits and incentives from installing our services
- ▶ Tailored unique solar paneling system for individual homeowner needs

Account Executive @ Time Warner Cable

January 2014 - July 2014 // Queens, NY

- ▶ Top ten in regional sales during the months of May and June, surpassing goals by a 150% margin
- Marketed products directly to prospective clients and educated current clients on new deals and products
- Converted customers from competitors and exceeded monthly goals as part of the "win-back" initiative from the FiOS team converting approximately 150 customers during tenure

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS/Sass, PHP

Libraries & Frameworks

¡Query, React, Node.js, Express, EJS, MongoDB, SQL, Bootstrap, Material Design Bootstrap, Materialize

Tools & Platforms

Git, Netlify, Heroku, Figma, Wordpress

Education

General Assembly

2020 - 2020 // Remote

Software Engineering Immersive Certification Program

Baruch College, City University of New York

2018-2019 // New York, NY

Bachelor of Business Administration, Management

Bronx Community College, City University of New York

2018 - 2019 // Bronx, NY

Associate in Performing Arts

Projects

Destination Ratr

Travel blog post site built with React, PHP, and PostgreSQL in which you can rate and share your experiences

Scriven

Code snippets notes app that integrates code with regular text built using the PERN stack (PostgreSQL, Express, React, and Node.js)

Iconic Baseball

A web app in which you can post pictures of baseball's most iconic moments. Built with the MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React, and Node.js)

Interests

Travel, Sports, Self-help books, Motivational Content, Personal Finance